Guide to the Ronald Reagan Library Records
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Ronald Reagan Library records
1980-1987
1984-1987
SC0423
Stanford University. Planning Office.
3 Linear feet
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, plans, and notes, 1980-1987; brochures and correspondence from architectural firms, 1984-1985; and site plans and maps.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Provenance
Administrative transfer, 1987.
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
Stanford University was considered but not chosen as the site for the Ronald Reagan Presidential Library.
Description of the Collection
Correspondence, memoranda, reports, plans, and notes, 1980-1987; brochures and correspondence from architectural firms, 1984-1985; and site plans and maps.
Access Terms
Reagan, Ronald, 1911-; Stanford University. Planning Office.; Presidents--United States--Archives.
Collection Contents
- Records
  - Reagan Library Area Plan: Notes and Drafts, 1986-87 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Program Statement for The Ronald Reagan Presidential Library, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Site Planning Workbook 1 - Ronald Reagan Library at Stanford University, 1980-84 (Box 1)
  - Site Planning Workbook 2 - Ronald Reagan Library at Stanford University, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Site Planning Workbook 2 - Ronald Reagan Library at Stanford University, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Ronald Reagan Library Planning Notes (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Ronald Reagan Library Planning Notes, 1986-87 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Phil Williams Reagan Library Planning Committee Notes (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Arch itect Brochures (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Spencer Associates Architects and Planning - Brochure and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Skilling Ward Rogers Barkshire Inc. - Brochure and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Simon Martin-Vegue Winklestein Morris - Brochure and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence with Architects, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Johnson Guthrie Associates - Brochure and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Booth/Hansen & Associates - Brochures and Correspondence with Phil Williams (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Helmuth, Obata and Kassabaurn - Brochures and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Blount Construction and Engineering - Brochures and Correspondence (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Information on the Gerald Ford Library, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - ESA Planning And Environmental Services - Brochure and Correspondence, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - h/mt - Brochures and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - General Requirements for the Ronald Reagan Presidential Library, 1985 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Ronald Reagan Library - Area Plan, 1987 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Architectural Firms - Brochures and Correspondence, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Architectural Firms - Brochures and Correspondence, 1984-85 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Johnson and Ford Libraries - Notes and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Johnson and Ford Libraries - Notes and Correspondence, 1984 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Site plans and maps (Box Roll)